<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calvary Baptist Church</title>
    <description>Calvary Baptist Church in St. Peter, Minnesota</description>
    <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:20:30 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:20:30 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The House Becoming a Dream Home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking for that perfect place to live, that “DREAM HOME that exceeds even our own expectancies?” Search no more! That place is not made of brick &amp;amp; mortar, nor is it constructed of siding &amp;amp; shingles. The place to live and the person to live with makes all the difference when it comes to DREAM HOME HAPPINESS, and it’s all BIBLE-BUILT: “And let them make me a sanctuary; that I may dwell among them” (Exodus 25:8). That perfect place is predicated on His perfect plan: “Speak unto the children of Israel, that they bring me an offering … willingly with his heart” (v. 2). So: the HEART HOME IT IS, dwelling in Him with His Holy Spirit “oil for light” &amp;amp; “sweet incense”  (V. 6), In a communing love relationship; HE makes the house a home. It all depends on where you want to live and the PERSON dwelling with you!  “Let them make me a sanctuary”!”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/01/26/the-house-becoming/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/01/26/the-house-becoming/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Exceeding, Rewarding Exchange</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Any of those unpleasant emotions of fear that at times loom over our soul, that want a controlling change over our God blessed well-being?  Man’s fears:  Oh, they’re so real, yes they’re uninvited intruders, and they may happen to attach themselves to us all, even affecting God’s choice servants. “After these things the word of the LORD came unto Abram in a vision, saying, Fear not, Abram: I am thy shield, and thy exceeding great reward” (Genesis 15:1).  After Abram had been blessed with the Lord’s victorious conquest over the enemy (14:20), God came to him with the assurance that fear is also conquered: “Fear not Abram!”  The why: a shield!  The Who: The Lord was his shield.  Nothing negative in the world of fearfulness could bypass the Lord, OUR SHIELD!  Our hearts are under His sovereign protection, shielded, then giving to us His “exceeding great reward,” His peace!  Our spiritual assignment: Exchange our fears for His fear!  “Ye that fear the Lord, trust in the LORD: he is their help and their shield” (Psalm 115:11).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/01/19/an-exceeding-rewarding/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/01/19/an-exceeding-rewarding/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lifted</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Need a song in your heart, to lift that “at times” heavy heart of your’s, as you enter a new day, for the new year?  Rejoice, there is a REAL SONG FOR A REAL LIFE: YOUR’S, because of the new life God has given those “born-again (John 3:3)!  Here’s a Psalm that God’s people of old sang to experience His newness!  “For his merciful kindness is great toward us: and the truth of the LORD endureth for ever. Praise ye the LORD” (Psalm 117:2).  What a song of a Psalm: we can sing it for His mercy covers “the old” because of Calvary’s cross - the CAUSE for His song to be sung!  His loving kindness paves the way for the new &amp;amp; “is great toward us,” - the Spirit’s UNCTION prompting us to sing His song.  Then to solidify it all in our soul, we can sing His song with the Bible REALITY of “the truth of the Lord endureth forever!”   With that truth set in our hearts, we joyfully endure - forever!  Yes, it is all true; it’s all BIBLE!  Then, there remains only one wonderful, joyful response to it all, and yes it is a song as well.  The Psalmist could not contain it all, nor could he keep the newness song to himself; he sang it, and so can we:  “Praise the Lord!”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/01/12/lifed/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/01/12/lifed/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Brand New Newness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Need some spiritual newness in your new year that can stir your soul “out of oldness activity” into the new?  If you mind goes there, let your heart follow.  There exists the greatest Biblical soul venture that anyone can possess &amp;amp; practice: LOVE &amp;amp; LOVING (1 Corinthians 13:13)!  Btw, that spiritual exercise might be “old” to some, but to Jesus, He calls it NEW.  “A new commandment I give unto you, That ye love one another; as I have loved you, that ye also love one another” (John 13:34).  A new commandment generated by love, captivating your soul to newness, His love.  Which in turn will generate love from a soul transformed by that love, that can make the difference in another’s soul.  His love does that, exactly that, and makes the one loving and the one being loved feel NEW.  Could it be that is why HIS LOVE &amp;amp; LOVING with His brand of love is &amp;amp; always has been, and always will be NEW in His book!  It can be in your’s as well!  Make that LOVE NEW!  Obey love’s command, and experience a BRAND NEW NEWNESS!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/01/05/a-brand-new/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/01/05/a-brand-new/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>His Signature Script of Newness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Need some newness as we are all positioned at the cusp of an old year, now focusing our sights on the new?  Rejoice, the Lord has a more than ample supply of His newness headed in your direction, all made possible through throne-room proclamation.  “And he that sat upon the throne said, Behold, I make all things new. And he said unto me, Write: for these words are true and faithful” (Revelation 21:5).  “He said” it, we believe it, and what a great verse to APPLY for our newsness-needed life, in “all things!”  Our assignment: no, we can’t make our old life new;  better yet:  He can!  We can set our new year sights higher, and “behold” the newness, because He “makes” it so!”  As a new creation in Christ, old things pass away, and all things are becoming new (2 Corinthians 5:17).   Believe it: newness!   Behold it: newness! Become of it: newness!  A moment by moment new life comes from Him, all with His pronounced newness.  Just abide in Him (John 15:1-5) this coming year, because He’s the One who “makes all things new!”  “And he said unto me: “Write!”  May a new chapter be written with His “Signature Script of Newness” on the table of your heart.  Yes, He wants to do the writing; and yes, He can, because He is faithful &amp;amp; true.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2015/12/29/his-signature-script/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2015/12/29/his-signature-script/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
