<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calvary Baptist Church</title>
    <description>Calvary Baptist Church in St. Peter, Minnesota</description>
    <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 21:21:51 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 21:21:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Riverside Thanksgiving!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Prayer &amp;amp; its place in the Christian life is so essential, so true during this Thanksgiving season. Believers back in Bible times had a time &amp;amp; place for their heart conversation with their Lord:  “We went out of the city by a river side, where prayer was wont to be made” (Acts 16:13). They journeyed “out of the city” getting away from all its distractions &amp;amp; gathered by the peaceful place of the riverside.  What an example to follow, &amp;amp; what a time of year to pray &amp;amp; to give thanks to our Lord: “seeing He giveth to all: life and breath, and all things” (v. 25) . Find time at YOUR riverside place this Thanksgiving, a place without all the distractions of “the city” clamoring for your attention.  Find  that peaceful place, express your thanks to God for all His blessings bestowed on you &amp;amp; your loved ones!  Experience a RIVERSIDE THANKSGIVING this year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 19:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/11/21/a-riverside-thanksgiving/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/11/21/a-riverside-thanksgiving/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unto You First!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a blessing from Scripture being sent your way: “Unto you first God, having raised up his Son Jesus, sent him to bless you, in turning away every one of you from his iniquities” (Acts 3:26).  Yes, Jesus came to “bless you!” God sent Jesus with the prospect of the redemptive blessing sent to you! The spiritual connection for the blessing to be our’s has a qualifier, mankind must have a personal heart disconnect from that which thwarts the blessing.  Blessed be our forgiving Lord, &amp;amp; blessed be the forgiven, repentant sinner.  What a “heaven sent” - His Son &amp;amp; our sonship (I John 3:1).  Oh, walk in that forgiven state of fellowship to continue to receive &amp;amp; enjoy more of the blessings sent from the Son sent!  Make it an “Unto you first” (v. 26) blessing, by making Him first in your life!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 19:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/11/14/unto-you-first/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/11/14/unto-you-first/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Elected One!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hopes up? Will the right person be elected to solve the problems in a divided nation? Will things then get better &amp;amp; will our country then get back on the path for national prosperity? Yes, we need real answers and long for viable hope; however, the real hope for man is not found in any elected position held by man. Yes, men in office espousing godly principles in government can and will make a difference for our land, but the ballot box was never the panacea for our real well being! The real difference comes with a vote from the heart for One Who governs all &amp;amp; is over all. “Behold my servant, whom I uphold; mine elect, in whom my soul delighteth; I have put my spirit upon him: he shall bring forth judgment to the Gentiles” (Isaiah 42:1). Mark your ballot for “mine elect” &amp;amp; and allow His judgment to be your “soul’s delight!” Remember He is sovereign &amp;amp; He rules the nations, no matter who man puts in office! Yes, “He shall bring forth judgment …” (v. 1).  Rest your hope in the One Who knows how to rule! By the way, HE WILL!  “He ruleth by his power for ever; his eyes behold the nations” (Psalms 66:7).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 19:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/11/07/the-elected-one/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/11/07/the-elected-one/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trading Time!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Any anxieties, apprehensions or other fearful notions knocking on the door of your desired peaceful habitation?  Yes, that emotional “life-changer” wants in, and your address is marked well on the enemy’s GPS.  Here’s the blessing: the real “Life-Changer” wants in, and the powerful peace of our Lord exceeds that futile fear trying to erode with its influence on our hears and minds.  His name is Jesus, Who does still the waves, namely those storm-filled treacherous concerns!  He stands as Our Victor at the bow of our ship of faith, &amp;amp; calls us to spiritual action, namely trading in the human-held fear for Spirit endowed faith in His power to still the waves. Scripture time is marked time for the failing heart: “And he saith unto them, Why are ye fearful, O ye of little faith? Then he arose, and rebuked the winds and the sea; and there was a great calm” (Matthews 8:26). Just look to Him, long for Him, and LOVE HIM.  It is faith that worketh by love (Galatians 5:6), and  that powerful loving faith taps in to the ONE Who is the LIFE CHANGER. “There is no fear in love: but perfect love casteth out fear” (I John 4:18). Allow the ONE Who COMMANDS THE CALM, to give you that love-filled faith, as He stands at the bow of your ship - TODAY!  “Then He arose, and rebuked the winds and the sea and there was a GREAT CALM” (v. 26). &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/10/31/trading-time/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/10/31/trading-time/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Press Challenge!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Decisions, decisions, decisions - they are part of our life; being made every moment of every day.  We live with those right choices to further our love for life; but, then our hearts suddenly sink down in the murky memory of the decisions we cannot undo.  Your love for life is fulfilling when we make the right choices, especially with the Word that God has sent your way.  Yes, with your love for the the Word &amp;amp; the decision the Lord desires for the making in your life, He can change our heart’s disposition.  “Brethren … this one thing I do, forgetting those things which are behind, and reaching forth unto those things which are before, I press toward the mark of the high calling of God in Christ Jesus” (Philippians 3:13-14).  Instead of unwise decisions pressing on you, it’s time to do some forgetting and take the “REAL PRESSING CHALLENGE!”  It’s all about engaging in the high calling press, to lift you out of the low call press that reminds you of what you cannot change.  Let God change you, decide for you, by deciding for Him.  When you do, there are no more memories pressing on you to hurt you, to hinder you, or to harass you.  It all depends on the choice of who or what does the pressing.  When we press toward the high calling of God in Christ Jesus, we are well on our way in taking back our life &amp;amp; getting back to our love for life.  PRESS ON in your love for life, cherishing His love for your life. Your life is precious in His sight, and He does not want you to be bogged down with the old!  PRESS ON IN THE NEW with His love for life in you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/10/24/the-press-challenge/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/10/24/the-press-challenge/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Going Brings The Seeing!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Desiring an up close, personal view of your Lord enabling that “once again” beautiful-joyful walk with Him?  He is not so distant as we might presume, that is, from the seeing heart of obedient faith.  A close look at the invitation to His disciples to meet up with Him speaks volumes on “closing the distance!”  It’s all a spiritual matter of: “I’ll do what you want me to do Lord &amp;amp; go where you want me to go!”  Here’s the scripture that makes all the difference &amp;amp; takes care of all the distance concerning your seeing Him in your life today &amp;amp; everyday.  “Then said Jesus … go tell my brethren that they go into Galilee, and there shall they see me” (Matthew 28:10).  Faith that follows the command of the Christ leads to the coming to Christ, in a  face to face visual of the One we long to see “up close!”  Jesus is still speaking to the brethren (that’s us): “Go to me &amp;amp; you shall see me!”  Going brings the seeing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/10/17/going-brings-the-seeing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/10/17/going-brings-the-seeing/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Road Ready!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever traveled in the fog?  It’s not our choice driving experience of going somewhere; that is, until the sun rises &amp;amp; burns off that visual inhibitor.  How about going somewhere in that unwelcomed spiritual fog, with all those intense feelings of internal direction lost?  There is a Light that can burn through it all so we can see where we are headed once again.  With the power of His Word shining forth, we are “Road Ready” - out of the fog;  going &amp;amp; growing again. “But unto you that fear my name shall the Sun of righteousness arise with healing in his wings; and ye shall go forth, and grow …” (Malachi 4:2).  The Lord desires to do the “healing” of the spiritual engine of your life, get you on the road of life again, going somewhere in destinations divinely determined.. The key to starting that engine of life is given “unto you that fear my name” (v. 2).  Oh, love the Lord, serve Him, fear Him, and then watch Him do the fog burn!   “In thy light, we shall see light” (Psalm 36:9).  Road ready begins with being Word-ready!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/10/10/road-ready/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/10/10/road-ready/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Raiment Change!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Like what you’re wearing?  Dressed for success?  How about appreciation for the garb of spiritual success? The Lord can help us answer those questions of personal decor. He has the spiritually attractive garment that “fits all” &amp;amp; it is spiritually fashioned for all!  When we wear His robe of white given at salvation, be Biblically assured that it will never go out of fashion - it’s eternal. The designer garb from the Great Designer is your’s for the wearing: “And he answered and spake unto those that stood before him, saying, Take away the filthy garments from him. And unto him he said, Behold, I have caused thine iniquity to pass from thee, and I will clothe thee with change of raiment” (Zechariah 3:4).  The raiment change is ready for all who enter His redemptive dressing room.  The changed raiment comes from the One who can change the one desiring the “new look”  of the “new man” (Ephesians 4:24).  The new  spiritual garb will catch the eyes of the one who knows what to wear!  As we wear it, “we shall walk with HIM in white” (Revelation 3:4).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/10/03/the-raiment-change/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/10/03/the-raiment-change/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get out the Umbrella!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Need some rain?  The spiritual rain of God’s blessing can be poured out on “your land” &amp;amp; the showers of His can be your’s!  Here’s the “how” and it deals with the “know” in following the “Shower Maker!” Then shall we know, if we follow on to know the LORD: his going forth is prepared as the morning; and he shall come unto us as the rain, as the latter and former rain unto the earth” (Hosea 6:3).  His “going forth” has a direct parallel in OUR PERSONAL GOING FORTH in following the Lord.  His rain of blessing in the healing of our soul and the binding of the same Is WORD INCLUSIVE, all dealing with a revived HEART (living in him again life - v. 2).  Question: “How sure is this promise of an abundant life in our Lord?”  The answer from Hosea is clear &amp;amp; certain: “Thy judgments are as light that goeth forth” (v. 5).  His Word does and will go forth!  You can’t put out the light &amp;amp; you can’t stop HIS rain as you go forth in following Him! “Then ye shall know” (v. 3).  Get out the umbrella!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/09/26/get-out-the-umbrella/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/09/26/get-out-the-umbrella/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>His Barometer Difference</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Any words coming at you &amp;amp; to you that are making the difference, affecting the “internals” of your life.  The penetrating difference that words make (even your words) can be the barometer difference between “going on” or “giving up” in life.  Isaiah has the right Word for the right time, for  right thinking - for us. “O LORD, by these things men live, and in all these things is the life of my spirit: so wilt thou recover me, and MAKE ME TO LIVE” (Isaiah 38:16).  Question: just what were “all these things” that gave “life of the spirit” to the prophet?  Oh, those words of His, those God’s Words, were words of life giving spirit that made the barometer difference to “recover” Isaiah, &amp;amp; will get you going again as well.  Here then, are THOSE WORDS: “What shall I say? He hath with spoken unto me, and Himself hath done it” (verse 15).  What the Lord says, He will do: dictum factum (whatever is said is DONE)!  That means you can “Do Life!”  As Isaiah pondered, “What shall I say?”  The response:  our pondering is history, only one answer remains: nothing can be spoken or added when the Lord speaks Life giving words to our soul.  His Word power gives us life power - to keep us keeping on.  Jesus tells us: “The words that I speak unto you the are spirit, and they are LIFE” (John 6:63).  He can make the barometer difference; go on in your life giving challenges and “DO LIFE”  today!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/09/19/his-barometer-difference/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/09/19/his-barometer-difference/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
