<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calvary Baptist Church</title>
    <description>Calvary Baptist Church in St. Peter, Minnesota</description>
    <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 17:44:01 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 17:44:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What&#39;s in a name?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“What’s in a name?”  That’s an interesting question calling for interesting answers.  Take the name Jabez for example, concerning that Biblical question &amp;amp; answer study!  Jabez, the name speaks of “sorrow!”  There is a life-changing decision that he made; he didn’t live according to the name given him; rather he lived up to what the Lord could give him.  Scripture tells us so in his prayer:  “Jabez called on the God of Israel, saying, Oh that thou wouldest bless me indeed, and enlarge my coast, and that thine hand might be with me, and that thou wouldest keep me from evil, that it may not grieve me! And God granted him that which he requested” (I Chronicles 4:10).  Here’s the life-changing challenge: take what life has placed on your plate, lift it high in a Jabez prayer with all its Jabez misgivings, and be ready to receive a Jabez answer: “Granted!”  Life’s too short for sorrow too long.  Get the blessing for you, the coast enlarged before you, God’s hand on you, evil chased from you, and the granted request coming at you.  Be a Jabez, not in name, but a Jabez in being blessed!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/06/13/whats-in-a-name/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/06/13/whats-in-a-name/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Clearer Vision!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;How are things looking lately?  Are we thrilled with the sights set before us?  Is “bleak” the comeback word from pending, looming despair!  If so, the answer just may be emanating from the eyes of our humanity, that part of us that “LIFE HITS HARD!”  Oh, there’s clearer vision - from our Lord.   Every moment in life is precious, and we must take time to view that life through the eyes of faith. “For we walk by faith, not by sight” (2 Corinthians 5:7).  Things change in the faith walk because our view of life has a different perception in the faith walk.  The reason: faith taps us into how the Lord is overlooking it all with His divine purpose in view.  Oh, take another look at your life with His look UPON you in your life!  See as He sees - YOU!  He sees all of YOU; He’s looking over it, all for YOU;  He lovingly works it all out to the good purpose of His will for YOU when we love Him in our faith walk (Romans 8:28).  Faith tells us so, and faith’s walk leads us so,  and faith helps us to view that which the Lord has specially designed for this who “walk by faith; and not by sight!”  That’s clearer vision, seeing as He views it all! Take another look, in faith!  “The LORD will perfect that which concerneth me” (Psalm 138:8).  Praise the Lord, it’s not so bleak after all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/06/06/clearer-vision/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/06/06/clearer-vision/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Feeling Refreshed while Walking!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Exhausted, tired, worn out in the walk, namely in your spiritual walk?  Would you believe that there can be rest for our soul as we go forward one step at a time in a Word based faith-walk!  It begins with what the Lord says about that faith-walk &amp;amp; the place on which our faith is positioned!  We walk by faith in practice, by holding on to the Word of faith in position, namely doctrine.  There is a challenging verse that can bring a rest-full walk into faith’s practice: “Thus saith the LORD, stand ye in the ways, and see, and ask for the old paths, where is the good way, and walk therein, and ye shall find rest for your souls” (Jeremiah 6:16).  Once we stand there, we can ask there, then when we ask there with a heart interest, we can see there.  Once we see there, we can believe there: then, seeing is believing, and believing is to “be living!”  It’s all about  the old &amp;amp; proven paths that God’s people of old have trod, and the Word documents that path as the “GOOD WAY!”  May it be said, “yes, that ‘Old Time Religion’ that was good enough for our fathers and their fathers is good enough for me!”  Why? because t’s more than a religion, it’s a relationship with our Lord, and He gives rest in the walk!   May the Lord remind you from Jeremiah’s encouragement that you can rest while walking with Him &amp;amp; that walk is the “Good Way!”  “FEELING REFRESHED WHILE WALKING!”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/05/30/feeling-refreshed-while-walking/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/05/30/feeling-refreshed-while-walking/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don&#39;t Cut Yourself Short!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Been “cut short lately?”  Could it be that what was meant to be for you never made it to your person &amp;amp; place in life?   Hopefully that “cutting short” possession wasn’t occurring in your spiritual realm.  It did happen to some Old Testament “shortsighted” &amp;amp; self-willed  people who “short-cutted” their relationship with their God &amp;amp; “took no heed to walk in the law of God” (2 Kings 10:31).  The tragic result:  “In those days the LORD began to cut Israel short” (v. 32).  No blessings, no prayers answered, no divine interventions; all because of “NO WALK WITH HIM!  Thank God for that revival breaking forth back then.  All because down deep in the heart of man, some of the people of God hunger for the Word of God and His activity in their soul,  as seen in the context.  Things changed when “Jehoiada made a covenant between the LORD … and the people , that they should be the LORD’s people” (11:17).  Oh, the Lord has promised His blessings upon the lives of those who are His people walking with Him, praying to Him, living for Him, serving Him, faithful to Him, speaking for Him, worshiping Him, in your place of fellowship together with the “people of God” ALL FOR HIM.  Oh, don’t cut yourself short of what was meant for you. “No good thing will He withhold from them that walk uprightly (Psalm 84:11). All for the people of God - oh, be one of them!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/05/23/dont-cut-yourself-short/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/05/23/dont-cut-yourself-short/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No Limping in the Joy-Walk!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Need some extra spiritual muscle to grace that life of your’s during those tough, even tearful times. They do come to us all, don’t they?  Well, then it’s time to look to our Lord to take care of that soul’s need of strength, as we find our way back to the starting gate of our daily walk and run with Him.  Everyday strength is God-sent, delivered to the one living the life that God has called us to.  Life “in Him” is all about Him.  An up &amp;amp; running life is found in His life: grace-favored, grace sent, grace delivered, all leading to a grace-life that is joy-strengthened!  The Word tells us so:  “In his favor (grace) is life: weeping may endure for a night, but joy cometh in the morning” (Psalm 30:5).  Yes, JOY COMETH!  He gives it; we don’t have to chase it. It comes to us when we come to Him and live for Him.  We don’t have to limp along when we possess God’s spiritual grace-muscle of joy. The joy of the Lord is your strength (Nehemiah 8:10).  Here’s our joy assignment: Get JOY-STRONG in the WORD-STRONG FOR THE JOY-WALK: “Strengthened with all might, according to his glorious power, unto all patience and long-suffering with JOYFULNESS” (Colossians 1:11). Yes, then “JOY COMETH!”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/05/17/no-limping-in-the/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/05/17/no-limping-in-the/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let the Planting Begin!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let the planting begin! It’s all about sowing in the now and the reaping to certainly come.  The Word of God is clear; what a  man sows he will reap (Galatians 6:7 ).  Then, what a harvest: the sower turned reaper accrues manifold more than his initial deposit in that soil of life.  As for the seeds for the sower, oh select them carefully and with great prospect!  As for the harvest, it can be a time of rejoicing.  Oh, allow the Lord to choose His right seed, and allow His right Spirit to condition and prepare your right soil.  A joyful harvest is then all in the making, that gladness of heart guaranteed to you, backed up with Scripture:  “Light is sown for the righteous, and gladness for the upright in heart” (Psalm 97:11). Let the light of the Lord be turned on in the happy heart of his people &amp;amp; let planting begin (with His seeds of course)!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/05/10/let-the-planting/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/05/10/let-the-planting/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Possible and Powerful</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you thought to yourself lately, “Things don’t look so good!”  Then along side of that despair came the words within: “Looks to me like an impossible situation!”  Oh, take heart, because the dreary things change with His Word spoken within &amp;amp; that soul’s overcast of your’s is chased away with the Son-look that Jesus gives to you and upon you: “And Jesus looking upon them saith, With men it is impossible, but not with God: for with God all things are possible” (Mark 10:27).  So true!  With God “ALL THINGS ARE POSSIBLE!”  Allow Jesus to be “looking upon you” (v. 27), because when He does, he looks also upon those impossibles (as we view them) intruding their wormy way into our lives. With His look redefined as our’s &amp;amp; with His new look captured in our now focused spiritual sights, we see the possible linked together with the powerful.  Both HIS and from HIM!   It’s all a matter of dealing with how we look at life’s situations.  Allow his “looking upon you” (v. 27),  tied together with His view of our difficulties, and you will have a new OUTLOOK, all empowered by faith rewarded with His powerful possibilities. “Got any rivers uncrossable? Got any mountains you can’t tunnel through? God specializes in the impossible! He does things we cannot do! Take that new look through the eyes of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/05/03/possible-and-powerful/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/05/03/possible-and-powerful/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The &#39;Up and Going Again&#39; Spiritual Tonic for Your Soul</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Running on empty?   Could be?  Maybe?  Well, here’s a “SHALL BE” that can be infused in our lives to take care of and to fill that empty.  Please consider two essentials for us all to “keep on keeping on!” -  Life and light!  We need both to operate our spiritual system; the source for both life and light is a given by our Lord, and the spiritual “get up and go” power they both bring is a promise of spiritual fuel from our Lord: “For with thee is the fountain of life: in thy light shall we see light” (Psalm 36:9).  His fountain of life ushers forth to refresh us, motivating us by setting us on our way; and His light is shining forth, for us to see what we can be for Him to keep us on that way.  What a motivating spiritual influence!  Both life and light have power enough to dispel that depressing darkness  convoluting our way.  Things change WITH HIM!  Being in Him and Him in you bring a glorious “full of life” daily walk.  Living in and for Him brings that moment by moment “up and going” motivation from and for our Lord; &amp;amp; that life-walk can be translated as spiritual energy for your soul, a Biblical tonic of spiritual Geritol, if you will.  Need some?  Receive some!  Get some!  The essentials for your daily walk with Him comes fresh off the counter of the Spiritual Physician (Jeremiah 8:22);  HE knows how our spiritual system works, can get working again, and keep working - again.  His life and His light will do the job!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/04/26/the-up-and/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/04/26/the-up-and/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Grace-Venture for You</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a joint venture: God REMAKING the man to fulfill His glorious purpose in a life chartered by Him.  What a creative work, as we allow SUFFERING to tap us into His grace for His glory.  Suffering is God’s pathway to a glorious life lived for Him.  Yes, tough times, heart-aches, dashed dreams, illness, and all the tough roads traveled upwards can be redefined with two powerful Biblical words:  grace &amp;amp; glory.  “But the God of all grace, who hath called us unto his eternal glory by Christ Jesus, after that ye have suffered a while, make you perfect, stablish, strengthen, settle you” (I Peter 5:10).  There is a specific calling that the Lord desires, and can only be accomplished in us, through suffering. That divine glorious calling comes to the life that accepts “suffering awhile” (remember it’s seasonal, v. 10); then that life is grace-perfected (matured), grace-stablished (firm in soul), grace-strenghtened (Spirit empowered), &amp;amp; grace-settled (unmoveable).  The Lord is the only ONE who knows what type of Christian character we need for His glorious plan to be fulfilled in our lives.  It’s a “call unto his eternal glory” (v. 10).  Joint venture?  Oh yes!  Let’s take a fresh, second look at those two words: grace &amp;amp; glory.   GRACE can spiritually dismiss the negative, and the “oh, so human” mindset that plagues us in our association with suffering, and THEN THAT GRACE, GOD’S GRACE awakes us to His GLORY, now possessing a life molded, and in a “joint venture” to be used for His glory.  Allow that grace venture to become a grace adventure lived out with His glorious life with-in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/04/19/a-grace-venture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/04/19/a-grace-venture/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Spiritual Engine of Life</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Need a blessing from the Lord today to keep that spiritual engine of your’s in tune? As an obedient son to His loving Father we all can rest assured that His goodness to be bestowed is well on it’s way.  He has the heart to give the blessing, the power to deliver it, &amp;amp; the authority to make it real!  It’s all about the Father’s “special order” blessing for His obedient children. Ordered?  Absolutely!  Here’s the order-power found in the Word to deliver that blessing that we all desire from our Father:  “The LORD commanded the blessing, even life for evermore” (Psalm 133:3).  With an appreciative look at all the blessings coming from the Lord, as seen in the entirety His Word, and a closer look at today’s text, there is a “blessedness of being blessed” for you.  The real blessing accompanying the blessing is “Life Forever More!”  Blessed people are full of life because they are living in the blessing and the blessed state of their Living God.  Oh dwell in the blessed submission of His Spirit &amp;amp; to His Word; as you do, you have the blessing of His Life commanded to you, His blessed  Life for you, &amp;amp; His Life to be lived in you, all in the blessed state, HIS -  with you today &amp;amp; everyday - that translates into Life Forever More.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 06:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/04/12/the-spiritual-engine/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://saintpetercalvarybaptistchurch.com/2016/04/12/the-spiritual-engine/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
